# Miguel Gutierrez Kamayd

Entrepreneur & Software Architect | kamayd@gmail.com | +1(786)768-1914

# Summary

Professional, highly qualified and passionate full stack Software Architect based in Miami, FL, USA. Strong hands-on experience in software applications design and development. Self-motivated with good problem-solving skills and fast learning abilities, used to designing quality software under strict deadlines.

I have created several mobile and web apps using web technologies like Ionic, Angular, AWS and others for over 10 years. I co-founded Pooler Inc. and lead the pooler team in the development of the pooler.io app from idea to product. I have been working with many clients around the world developing apps used by millions of users.

# **Skills Highlights**

- Entrepreneurship, Leadership, Team building
- Problem Solving
- C# and .Net (ASP.NET MVC, Nancy)
- Unit Test: TDD, Xunit, Jasmine, Mocha
- AWS (DynamoDB, Lambda, S3, Cognito, Serverless)
- JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular JS (1.x, 2+), Ionic (1, 2+), React JS, Jquery, Gulp, Grunt, Bower, CSS, Sass, Less, Yeoman, NPM, Node, HTML
- SQL, MySql, Postgres, Redis, EntityFramework.
- Desktop: WPF

# **Previous Positions Highlights**

<u>Co-founder and President</u> at Pooler Inc., Miami, Florida, USA.

March 2017 to April 2018.

I co-founded and lead the development of the pooler.io app. Pooler.io is an app for playing states lottery from your phone. Some of my accomplishment as president of Pooler Inc.:

- Designed and lead the development of the **pooler.io** mobile app/landing page/backend APIs from idea to product in users hands.
- Develop computer vision technologies and several admin tools allowing to process lottery tickets in seconds.

Senior Web Developer at Carnival Cruise Lines, Miami, Florida, USA.

# July 2015 to March 2017.

As part of the guest technologies team at Carnival I had amount others responsibilities: Lead the frontend team, introduce and try new technologies, review poll request, performed interviews, and solve multiple design and efficiency challenges.

I have designed and implemented among others projects:

- Shorex mobile app for selling excursions to the guests onboard (IOs/Android/Web).
- Pixels mobile app for selling photos to the guests onboard (IOs tablet and IOs/Android phone).
- **SEAMS** internal tool for scheduling and managing voyage data on the ships.
- **OMS** Order Management System. Services for selling/managing photos on the ships.
- Sherlock Admin UI internal tool for reporting and inventory of photos on the ships.

<u>Senior Software Developer</u> at Business Systems Ltd (BSL), London, United Kingdom.

March 2013 to January 2015.

Designed and Implemented, with others members of the team, several projects for multiple clients like the Bank of England, National Health Service (NHS), National Air Traffic Services (NATs), UK police forces and others.

- WordWatch v5 is the latest digital call recording platform from BSL.
- **Digivoice** is a digital call recording platform. It provides an objective record of inbound and outbound phone activity which can be used to develop your team's telephone communication skills. It helps to identify areas where there is a clear training or coaching need as well as assessing the effectiveness of the system as a whole.
- CODES tailored recording applications relevant to the police and associated law
  enforcement agencies, BSL has developed the next generation of interview and
  evidence recording technology, incorporating digital audio and video. It's suitable for
  those organizations which require secure and accurate evidence as part of their
  interview process.
- OPEX Callcraft provides hosted telephony applications for general businesses and contact centers thereby relieving you of the need to install and maintain expensive capital equipment on your own premises.

<u>Software Developer</u> at National Institute of Digital Research (ICID), Havana, Cuba. September 2010 to September 2012

Designed and implemented, with others members of the team, several projects:

 Galaxy Plus is a system that provides real-time centralized information obtained from different physiological parameters monitors in an intensive-care unit. • Solutions for continuous monitoring of ECG signal is a system for monitoring the electrocardiogram signal of a patient, while he performs normal life activities in order to make an accurate diagnosis.

### Education

B.S. Computer Science, University of Havana, Cuba. 2005-2010

**Courses Included:** Software Engineering, Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, Databases, Computer Networks, Compilers, Number Theory, Graphs, Combinatorics and Probability, Programming Languages, Computability Theory, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics.

#### **Honors & Awards**

Bronze Medal at the Mathematics Olympics for Spanish speakers "V OLYMPIC OF MAY" May 1999.

Participated and won gold and silver medals in national math competitions at Cuba. (2001-2004)

#### Courses

ForwardJS conference + 2 Workshops (Extreme Web Performance by Max Firtman and Deep Dive into Angular 2 by Aysegul Yonet)

July 2016 (Duration: 4 days) Silicon Valley, CA, USA.

Mark Rendle's Single Page Applications with Angular JS & .NET October 2013 (Duration: a week), Skills Matter 116-120 Goswell Road EC1V 7DP, London, United Kingdom.

## Languages

English, Spanish and Limited proficiency in French

#### More info

My resume online (http://kamayd.com)

My linkedIn profile

(https://www.linkedin.com/in/miguelgutierrezkamayd)